# Lewis Muema

#### CONSTRUCTION PROJECT MANAGER

<u>kavingajr@gmail.com</u> +25471516789 <u>https://lewismuema.github.io/</u> Voi- Taita Taveta

#### **SUMMARY STATEMENT**

Experienced graduate construction project manager with two years of experience in the construction industry delivering projects. Collaborative team player with a strong focus on productivity, attention to detail, and client satisfaction. Proficient in using project management tools, techniques and software to ensure timely delivery of projects, within projected budget and with the required standards.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

April 2024- Present

Site Surveyor, Proposed Fanaka Aluminum Plant – Athi River, Machakos County

- Successfully completed setting out of three warehouses and servants' quarter using Total Station Machine.
- Marking out levels at required points using dumpy level so as to guide craftsmen.
- Conveying the Project Manager's instructions and interpreting drawings to foremen and craftsmen and following up on them.
- Controlling quality of construction works by ensuring formwork and steelworks are as
  required before concreting, supervising concreting to ensure the correct slump, sufficient
  vibration and stability of formwork is maintained all through and ensuring masons lay blocks
  correctly in the marked positions whilst achieving plumbness.
- Supervision of excavation works ensuring it is done precisely in the marked area, to the
  correct depth, ensuring occupational safety and maintaining maximum productivity of
  machinery whilst monitoring for underground utilities.
- Structural detailing of drawings and translating drawings from Mandarin to English so as to be easily understandable by foremen and crastsmen.

July 2022 – February 2024

**Construction Management Trainee,** Chawucha Holdings – Voi, Taita Taveta County

- Oversaw project scope, timeline and budget ensuring coordinated and successful completion of 4+ residential and infrastructure projects.
- Mitigated high project costs by reviewing the existing material procurement procedures and efficiently managing a team of 60+ workers.
- Monitored project progress and effectively communicated with clients and stakeholders.
- Devised a solution to solve the challenge of high rate of worker absenteeism in the beginning of the week.

August - November 2021

Construction Management Attaché, Jedi General Contractors Ltd – Voi, Taita Taveta County

- Calculated and evaluated productivity of workers on site ensuring adherence to time and budget.
- Assisted in project quality control on site ensuring compliance to standards and specifications.
- Periodically presented site progress reports ensuring the client and company administration are adequately informed on the project progress.

#### **EDUCATION**

September 2018 – October 2022

**Bachelor of Technology in Construction and Property Management,** Kirinyaga University Courses included Construction Technology, Structures, Measurement of Civil Works, Project Management, Project Monitoring and Evaluation, Computer-Aided Design (CAD), Project Feasibility studies and Appraisal.

#### **SKILLS**

Project management Setting out Communication
Project quality control Project scheduling Teamwork
Risk management Budgeting Leadership
Microsoft Project Microsoft Excel AutoCAD
Programming ArchiCAD

### ASSOCIATIONS AND CERTIFICATIONS

**Association of Construction Managers of Kenya (ACMK):** Technician Member.

Membership Number: T005

Project Management Institute: Project Management Professional (PMP): In progress.

## **REFERENCES**

References available upon request.